https://www.compub.com/privacy

Sign in
Hi, looks like you're visiting us from the UK.
Please click here to visit compub.co.uk.
UK
Ireland
ChristmasMacMacBook Pro 13"MacBook Pro 16"MacBook AiriMaciMac ProMac miniAccessoriesiPadiPad ProiPad AiriPadiPad mini 5CasesApple Pencil
Compare
iPhoneiPhone 12 Pro MaxiPhone 12 ProiPhone 12 miniiPhone 12iPhone 11iPhone XRiPhone SEAccessories
WatchApple Watch Series 3Apple Watch SEApple Watch Series 6Bands
TVApple TV HDApple TV 4KApple TV AccessoriesMusiciPod TouchBeatsAirPodsAirPods ProAirPods Max
AccessoriesCases, Straps & MountsAdapters & CablesDisplaysPower SupplyStorageMice, Keyboard,
StylusAudioJUKU
Native Union
JOBY
Education.
Privacy
Compu b respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This Privacy Notice will inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our website (regardless of where you visit it from) and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you. This Privacy Notice is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific areas set out below. Alternatively you can download a pdf version of the policy here. Please also use the Glossary to understand the meaning of some of the terms used in this Privacy Notice.
3. How is your personal data collected?
We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:
3.1 Direct interactions.
You may give us your Identity, Contact and Financial Data filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email, or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
make a purchase online
create an account on our website
subscribe to our newsletter
request marketing to be sent to you
enter a competition, promotion or survey
Apply for a job in our "Careers" section
give us some feedback
submit a query through the Contact Us form
3.2 Automated technologies or interactions.
As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, and other similar technologies. We may also receive Technical Data about you if you visit other websites employing our cookies. Please see our cookie policy for further details.
3.3 Automated technologies or interactions.
We may receive personal data about you from various third parties as set out below:
Technical Data from the following parties:
analytics providers such as Google
advertising networks such as Google and Facebook
search information providers such as Google and Bing
Contact, Financial and Transaction Data from providers of technical, payment and delivery services such as Ingenico.
4. How we use your personal data
4.1 Lawful basis
We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances where:
we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you
it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests
where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than in relation to sending third party direct marketing communications to you via email. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us at privacy@biconic.co.uk
4.2 Purposes for which we will use your personal data
We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.
Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us at privacy@biconic.co.uk if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.
Purpose/ActivityType of dataLawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest
To register you as a new customer
(a) Identity (b) Contact
performance of a contract with you
To process and deliver your orders: (a) communicating with you (b) manage payments (c) Deliver goods
(a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Financial (d) Transaction (e) Marketing and Communications
performance of a contract with you
To manage our relationship with you which will include: (a) notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy (b) asking you to complete a survey
(a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Profile (d) Marketing and Communications
(a) performance of a contract with you (b) necessary to comply with a legal obligation (c) necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products and services and develop our offerings)
To enable you to partake in a prize draw or competition
(a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Profile (d) Usage (e) Marketing and Communications
(a) performance of a contract with you (b) necessary for our legitimate interests (to offer additional features to our customers)
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)
(a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Technical
(a) necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise) (b) necessary to comply with a legal obligation
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you on our website, third party websites and social media channels, and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you
(a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Profile (d) Usage (e) Marketing and Communications (f) Technical
necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products and services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)
To use data analytics to improve our website, offers, marketing, customer relationships and experiences
(a) Technical (b) Usage
necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our various offerings, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about offers that may be of interest to you
(a) Identity (b) Contact (c) Technical (d) Usage (e) Profile
necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products and services and grow our business)
4.3 General marketing
We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising. We have established the following personal data control mechanisms set out in paragraphs 4.4 – 4.8.
4.4 Promotional offers from us
We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing).
You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us, received a product or service from us, or if you provided us with your details have not opted out of receiving that marketing.
4.5 Third-party marketing
We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company outside Compu b for marketing purposes.
4.5 Opting out
You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by contacting us at privacy@biconic.co.uk at any time. This will not apply to order confirmation or invoice emails for items you have purchased.
Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a purchase of a product or service.
4.6 Cookies
You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. For more information about the cookies we use, please see our cookie policy.
4.7 Change of purpose
We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us at privacy@biconic.co.uk.
If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.
Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.
5. Disclosures of your personal data
5.1
We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 4 above:
Internal Third Parties as set out in the Glossary
External Third Parties as set out in the Glossary
Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets; alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them; if a change happens to our business, then the new owners or newly acquired businesses may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this Privacy Notice.
5.2
We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.
6. International transfers
We do not transfer your personal data outside the European Economic Area (EEA).
7. Data security
7.1
We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
7.2
We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable supervisory authority or other regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.
8. Data retention
8.1
We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.
8.2
To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.
8.3
By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for six years after they cease being customers for tax and other legal purposes.
8.4
In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see below for further information.
8.5
In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.
9. Your legal rights
9.1
Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. Please click on the links below to find out more about these rights:
9.2
If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us at privacy@biconic.co.uk.
9.3
You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.
9.4
We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.
9.5
We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.
10. Glossary
10.1 Lawful Basis
Legitimate Interest means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best offering and the best and most secure experience; we make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests; we do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law); you can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us at privacy@biconic.co.uk.
Performance of Contract means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.
Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.
10.2 Third Parties
Internal Third Parties: Other companies in the BiCONIC Group (to which Compu b belongs) based in the EEA that provide IT and system administration services and marketing services to the Biconic Group.
External Third Parties
service providers based in Ireland, UK and in Netherlands who provide IT and system administration services, goods deliveries
professional advisers acting as processors or controllers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based in the EEA who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services
the Revenue Commissioners, regulators and other authorities acting as processors or joint controllers based in Ireland who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.
11. Your Legal Rights
You have the right to:
Request access: to your personal data (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
Request correction: of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.
Request erasure: of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.
Object to processing: of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have a compelling legitimate ground to process your information which overrides your rights and freedoms.
Request restriction of processing: of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.
Request the transfer: of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.
Withdraw consent at any time: where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain offerings to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.
Products
Mac
iPad
iPhone
Apple TV
Watch
AirPods
Accessories
Business online stores
Interested in a business opportunity?
Education online stores
Interested in educational opportunities?
Join!
Talk to an Expert: 1850 668888
Our stores
Our Dublin Stores
111 Grafton Street, Dublin
Dundrum Town Centre, Dublin
Pavilions Shopping Centre, Dublin
121 O'Connell Street, Limerick
17 Opera Lane, Cork
Liosban, Galway
Compu b HQ IRE, Dublin 12
Selfridges, Oxford St. London
Corporate Office & HQ UK, Milton Keynes
Follow us on Social Media
© Compu b Retail Limited
Ireland: Unit B1, Calmount Business Park, Dublin 12, Registration No. 639996
UK: 23 Erica Road, Stacey Bushes, Milton Keynes, MK12 6HS, Registration No. 7034450
*The last date to place your order for home delivery prior to Christmas is Friday 18 December, this date applies to in-stock items. Out of stock items cannot be guaranteed for delivery before Christmas
Back to top
